Kiran Methuku

Full Stack Web Developer

in /kiranmethuku0831 kiranmethuku.com

PROFILE

I'm a web developer with a user-driven mindset. I design and build applications that are engaging and intuitive to navigate. Most importantly, I believe in delivering value continuously by shipping fast, quality code. On top of my technical skills, I have experience in market research, project management, and client relations.

SKILLS

JavaScript/TypeScript React Redux Express Node PostgreSQL

Sequelize

MongoDB

Mongoose

Git

HTML

BEM CSS

Mocha

Jest

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer, Fitome 🗆

2021 – present

- Built a client management PWA for personal trainers using React with Next.js
- Implemented state management with Redux Toolkit
- Designed and built an extensive relational database using PostgreSQL with Sequelize
- Set up REST back end with Express.js

Full Stack Developer, Cardshare

2021 – present

November 2018 -

November 2019

- Designed and built a flashcard sharing application using React with Next.js
- Implemented authentication with Firebase
- Set up REST back end with Express.js and MongoDB
- Created a cross-platform compatible UI using BEM CSS

Project Manager & Consultant, The MarkeTech Group

- Managed multinational quantitative and qualitative market research projects
- Designed study tools using methodologies such as choice-based-conjoint, cascading price, and Van Westendorp
- Analyzed and synthesized data into clear, actionable client reports
- Presented deliverables to client teams consisting of international marketing and product managers and C-suite

EDUCATION

Quantitative Psychology B.S., University of California Davis

2015 - 2017

CS Courses: C++, Data Structures

Software Engineering Immersive, Codeworks

Full Stack Web Development

2021

REFERENCES

Christian Renaudin, CEO & Founder, The MarkeTech Group crenaudin@themarketechgroup.com, (530) 792-8400 x302